I lived much better under
мне жилось намного лучше при
Yanukovych, under that president
Януковиче вот при том президенте
Yanukovych, much better than in 14 when
Януковича намного лучше чем в 14 когда
he was gone, right Yes And now Yes,
его не стало правильно Да А теперь Да
it's clear, what's clear, and then the
это понятно вчем понятно а
Cossacks Yes, but now, look,
пер казаки Да а вот сейчас смотрите
now Putin is Russia Here you are, 2 years,
сейчас уже Путин Россия Вот вы 2 года
Russia officially, if you
Россия официально если
take, if you
взять если
take a year and three or something Yes, it doesn't matter, I'll
взять год и тре или чет Да неважно
tell you honestly Life wasn't better in 1913,
скажу честно В тринадцатом не жилось
yes, maybe, look I don't understand,
лучше да может смотрите Я не понимаю
maybe it would have been better if Yanukovych
может лучше было бы чтобы Президентом
had been the President of Russia
России был
Hello Oh, hello, I'm
Янукович Здравствуйте О здравствуйте Я
from the city of Khmelnitsky, where are you
из города Хмельницкий Вы
from? Well, should I name you a city or a
откуда Я из Ну вам город назвать или
region, like a city, street,
область как город улицу
house, no, street there, I won't name the city of
дом нет улицу там не назову город
Antratsit Antratsit, I know, it's
Антрацит Антрацит о знаю это
occupied territory, yes,
оккупированная территория да
see How what, well, this is Russia now, it's
см Как что ну это да это Россия сечас
like, it's like, now, wait, how is it with us,
это типа это сейчас подожди как он у нас
Kadiyevka Yes, not Kadiyevka, it was Stakhanov, in
кадиевка Да не кадиевка это Стаханов был
short, I understand And you, you, it turns out, you
короче понял А вы вы вы типа получается
lived in this Antratsit in 1914,
жили в этом Антраците в четырнадцатом
yes, and to Chech, tell me, in short,
да ну и до чече скажите вот короче
compare life now in Antratsit and in
Сравните сейчас жизнь в Антраците и в
2013 when
2013 году когда лучше
life is better in the thirteenth Well in 2013 So
живётся в тринадцатом Ну в 2013 году Так
you lived in Antratsit and now 2024 in
вот вы жили в Антраците и сейчас 2024 в
what year was life better in Antratsit
каком году лучше в Антраците жизнь была
I said In the thirteenth In the thirteenth I
я сказал В тринадцатом В тринадцатом
understood that is, it turns out Clearly,
понял то есть получается Чётко сразу
everything is sharp at once that is, it
резко всё то есть
turns out life was better
получается жилось лучше
yes under Yanukovych life was better that is, under Yanukovych
да при Януковича жилось лучше то есть
life was better than under Yanukovych life was better than After
при Януковиче жилось лучше чем После
him that is, and after him Putin became That
него то есть а после него стал Путин То
is, it turns out life was
есть получается при Януковиче жилось
better under Yanukovych than under Putin no Putin was not no stop stop there
лучше чем при Путине нет Путина не было
was no yes but now
нет стоп стоп не было да но сейчас уже у
you have already had 2 years since Putin
вас же 2 года как Путин
is 2 years but we are talking for 1 year yes but
есть 2 года но мы говорим за 1 год да но
look Yanukovych was also 3 years from 2010
смотрите Янукович тоже был 3 года с 2010
to 13 that is, in 3 years of Yanukovych it was
по 13 то есть за 3 года Януковича было
better than in 2 years
лучше чем за 2 года
Wait you
Подождите вы
jump we are now burning for the thirteenth
прыгайте мы сейчас горим за тринадцатый
year or for d chet yes In the thirteenth was
год или за д чет да В тринадцатом был
Look from there to the thirteenth was
Смотри с дего по тринадцатый был
Yanukovych and everything was fine and now
Янукович и всё было хорошо а теперь
Now you have Putin and everything is
Теперь у вас Путин и всё
bad My name is Vladimir What is your name My
плохо Меня зовут Владимир Как вас зовут
name is Andrey Andrey look Can you
зовут Андрей глядите Вы можете меня сес
catch me somewhere somehow no maybe yes
поймать где-то что-то как-то
maybe they caught Here But I am one of those
нет может да может и поймали Вот Но я из
people who do not hide the truth Here
тех людей которые не скрываю правду Вот
I am one of
и я из
those new so to speak Russians
тех новых так сказать россиян вот
who will not be right
которые не будут
here I can tell you honestly I do
пра вот я вам могу сказать честно меня
not need to be caught here I will tell you
не надо ловить вот я вам скажу
honestly in the year
чест в году
under that president Yakov it is much
вот при том президенте якови намного
better than when he was gone right
лучше чем в когда его не стало правильно
Yes And now Yes it is clear VM It is clear
Да А теперь Да это понятно ВМ Понятно
those Yes but now look now already
те Да а вот сейчас смотрите сейчас уже
Putin Russia Here you are 2 years Russia
Путин Россия Вот вы 2 года Россия
officially if you take that year
официально если взять тый год
and
и
so on life was
иче
not better there then maybe look
с там не жилось лучше то может смотрите
I do not understand maybe it would be better for
Я не понимаю может лучше было бы чтоб
Yanukovych to be the President of Russia than
Президентом России был Янукович чем
Putin if under Yanukovych there was
Путин если при Януковиче был
order it would be better not to
порядок лучше было бы чтобы Януковича не
overthrow Yanukovych for me personally yes yes Well look
свергать для меня лично да да Ну смотри
everything Here look he has already been overthrown Yes
всё Вот его смотри он его свергли уже Да
all this is already history and now Yanukovych is in
всё это уже история и теперь Янукович в
Rostov why do you people from Donbass
Ростове почему вам людям с Донбасса
Why didn't you nominate him Why did
Почему вы его не выдвинули Почему вы его
n't you nominate him for president of Russia
не выдвинули в президенты России
[music]
[музыка]
in order to nominate him for
для того чтобы выдвинуть его в
president of Russia at least He should have
президента России как минимум Он должен
run for
был баллотироваться
this For example, if you because
это Например если бы вы потому что
because you abandoned him
потому что вы его
Donbass before the elections said We demand
Донбас перед выборами сказали Мы требуем
that Yanukovych run for president of the
чтобы Янукович подался в президента
Russian Federation he would have seen that the
Российской Федерации он бы увидел что
people of Donbass really want him and would have
народ Донбасса хочет его действительно и
gone and submitted documents the people don't
пошёл бы подал документы народ доба не
want it why what's going on there people Well
хочет почему там то что дела народ Ну
because he's a
потому что он
traitor damn that is to say oh
предатель капец то есть получается ол
people Donbass it turns out under him the people of Donbass
народ Донбасс получается при нём донбасы
lived better than under Putin but he's a
жили лучше чем при Путине но он
traitor under him the
предатель при нём
region of Donbass I don't know how the whole of Ukraine is
регион Донбасс я не знаю как вся Украина
that is to say I can't judge because well I have
то есть не могу судить потому что ну я
n't
не
traveled I haven't traveled around Ukraine and
катался я не катался по Украине и не
I wasn't
путешествовал по Украине Я был в то
in my country at the time Well in Donbass so I
время у себя Ну на Донбассе так вот я
know how I lived so I can say clearly
знаю как жил я вот я могу сказать Чётко
and precisely under Yanukovych in 2007 I lived Okay Let
и точно при Януковиче в м году я жил
's do it Let's cut it like this
Хорошо Давайте Так давайте подрез
look Wait what look look
давайте так смотри Подожди что смотри
Wait I turned off the sound for you
смотри Подожди я тебе отключил звук
so you could listen to me  you interrupt
чтобы ты меня выслушал бы ты перебиваешь
Let's cut under Yanukovych
Давай подрез при Януковиче В тринадцатом
Life was better in 1913 than under Putin in 2024 Well,
жилось лучше чем при Путине в 2024 Да ну
I didn't finish yes or no, look again,
я не договорил да или нет смотри ещё раз
let me turn off the sound for you, repeat and
давай я тебе отключаю звук повторяю и
turn on the sound so you answer under
включу звук чтобы ты ответил при
Yanukovych Life was better in 1913 than
Януковиче В тринадцатом жилось лучше чем
under Putin in 2024
при Путине в 2024
Well,
Да
no, I don't want to answer your
нет я не хочу отвечать на ваш
question, I'm afraid, I'm afraid to say that yes, you're
вопрос боится боится сказать что да ты
me, I'm in trouble, lakha, mvsya, mvsya, I realized that
меня я беда лаха мвся мвся понял что
the mop, in short, smell
шваброй короче запах
Hello, cool bow, cool
Здравствуйте прикольный лук прикольный
cat, put down that screen, let's
котик опускай эту ширму давай
stretch, well, turn sideways It's cool
тянулась а ну боком повернись Прикольно
how it looks
как она выглядит
from the side, cool, well, blogger I understand that
сбоку прикольно ну блогер Я так понимаю
you are 18 years old, there is
вам 18 лет
something you communicate with,
есть есть чём общаетесь
but you just met these
да вот просто встретилось же это человек
20 people who say that they are not happy with
20 которые говорят что их не устраивает
my hat I ask a question And what is it that you are
моя шапка Я задаю вопрос А чем вас она
not happy with, they
не устраивает они
say or they say you can rub it, and
говорят или они говорят потирать можно а
I ask The next question And why is that the
я задаю Следующий вопрос А почему так
meaning of the undercoat
смыс подор
T A well  try to rub No I do
Т А ну попробуй потереть
n't
Не не
want It's
хочу
cool Well usually with hats Well
Прикольно вот Ну шапками обычно Ну
normal people like think that it's better not to lose it
нормальные люди типа считают что лучше
Well it's just not accepted
не потеря не потерять Ну так не принято
in normal society I don't know
просто в нормальном обществе Я не знаю
why it's like that maybe it's accepted in Ukraine but
почему так возможно в Украине принято но
I don't know why it's like that
я не знаю почему
And what do you talk about Yes,
так А чем общаешься
I don't really care about different things for example Well,
Да разном мне не особо важно например ну
a lot of things
Много о чём
there about whatever comes across
там о чём попадётся
that is, a person there, for example, a musician, I'll
то есть человек там допустим музыкант
discuss music there, a person Gamer, I don't know
музыку обсужу там человек Геймер не знаю
games, I'll discuss Well, like what's convenient, what's
игры обсужу Ну типа что удобно что
comfortable what do you think why Putin
комфортно как считаешь почему Путин
attacked
напал на
Ukraine there was no attack why And what was defense
Украину нападения не было
purely
было защита сугубо
defense Well it
защита Ну начиналась с защиты Да
started with
продолжилось захватом Ну начиналась
defense Yes it continued with seizure Well it started defense Well tell me Tell me about defense Yes tell
защиты Ну расскажи Раскажи про защиту Да
me after the Day of Adoption of the Donetsk
расскажи после Дня принятия Донецкой
People's Republic and Lugansk People's
народной и Луганской народной
Republic as an Independent State Well that is, more
Республики самостоятельным государством
precisely, the
Ну то есть точнее
republic
республикой
began shelling this
начались обстрелы этой
territory after which the so-
территории после чего началось так
called SVO began
называемое
this is what is considered specifically the so-
сво это что считается конкретно так
called war So in my homeland it
называемой войны Так у меня на родине
is accepted to say The first war began back in
принято говорить Первая война ещё в
1914 there were already their own
четырнадцатом году началась там уже свои
separate reasons Where is your homeland
были отдельные причины Где твоя родина
on
на ещё
Donetsk What year were you
Донецк С какого ты года
born the
рождения
sixth what is this  E what was 8 years old
шестой что это Е вчем 8 лет было
Well I remember Yes I remember everything well you don't
Ну помню Да всё хорошо помню ты не
remember it turns out yes Well why Why did
помнишь получается да Ну почему С чего
you get that I remember perfectly I understand
это вы взяли Я помню прекрасно
Tell me what
помню понял Расскажи что там
happened there Well it happened as I
происходило Ну происходило как на моей
remember it specifically I don't remember from the news
памяти было я конкретно По новостям не
but I remember how there was shelling how a
помню но помню как обстрелы были как у
shell that didn't explode flew into my yard
меня во двор прилетел снаряд не
And why you as an
разорвавшейся А изза чего ты как
eight year old yes why there
восьмилетний ребнок да из-за чего там
was shelling there Well it all started initially because of the
были Ну началось изначально всё из-за
Maidan then the protest stop stop stop stop stop stop stop stop not this to
Майдана потом протест стоп стоп стоп
you they
стоп стоп стоп стоп не это тебе это тебе
told you this I'll tell you what you saw
сказали Я вот скажу то что что ты видел
there well it's not good Okay Let's
там ну не хорошо Хорошо Давайте тогда с
look at it from the other side Let's see if they
другой стороны на это Посмотрим если мне
told me this How do you know are you a
это сказали Вы откуда знаете вы
politician did you participate Well that is you were
политик вы участвовали Ну то есть вы
directly involved I'm from Makeyevka I was born in What
прямо участ Я из Макеевки родом Я в чем
year did I leave
году выехал из
Makeyevka
Макеевки
well Yes I directly saw a war That's what I
нуде Да прямо войну видел Вот что войну
saw a war what did you see so that's uh Who was shooting at
видел что ты видел так вот ээ Кто кто по
you
тебе
Ukraine so so And how did you see
стрелял Украина так так А как ты видел
that Ukraine was shooting at it
что её стреляет Украина
m quite a stupid question
м достаточно глупый вопрос
and flying equipment That is the same planes
а летящая техника То есть те же самолёты
from the side of
со стороны
Ukraine shells flying at an angle And who
Украины снаряды летевший под углом А кто
with whom there  who fought with whom it
с кем там воевал кто с кем воевал там
turns out that the territory of the Donetsk People's
получается территория Донецкой народной
Republic Well, that is, Donbass What is it
Республики Ну то есть Донбасс Как
called and
называют и
Ukraine Well, I already said so, so I
Украин Ну я же сказал уже так так я так
understand that Ukraine had planes, tanks,
понимаю у Украины были самолёты танки
artillery, it abandoned everything, yes Well, what did the
артиллерия она всё кинула да Ну а что
ordinary miners of
было у простых Шахтёров
Donbass have? Who knows? No. And how did they
Донбасса Да кто знает не А чем они
fight off these planes? They didn't
отбивались от этих самолётов ничем не
fight back with anything at all. They didn't fight back with anything at all. I mean,
отбивались вообще ничем не отбивались в
why couldn't Ukraine
смысле а почему Украина 8 лет не могла
conquer Donetsk and Lugansk for 8 years if they
завоевать Донецк и Луганск если они
just had sticks There were miners here, here
просто с палками Были шахтёры тут тут
Russia can't, in short, hold back Ukraine,
Россия не может короче Украину сдержать
but here some miners with sticks
а тут какие-то с палками шахтёры
held back. Wow, there
сдержали Ничего
was a certain defense after the
себе защита определённая была после
capture of Crimea by Russia when Crimea, or rather the
взятия Крыма Росси когда Крым точнее
Maidans
майданы
began, the army itself, roughly speaking, that is, the
начались сама армия грубо говоря то есть
military entered the Russian
военные зашли Российской
Federation on the territory of Ukraine, reached
Федерации на территории Украины дошли до
Crimea, took Crimea and Well, this is the fourteenth,
Крыма взяли Крым и Ну это четырнадцатый
thirteenth I remember something, and having
тринадцатый Я помню что ли
taken Crimea, they returned and, damn,
а взяв Крым вернулись и [__]
stopped at the Donetsk People's
остановились на Донецкой Народной
Republic, the Lugansk People's Republic,
Республике Луганской Народной
in there were,
Республике во были
that is, Russian troops were
получается то есть российские воска были
in  fourteenth year Well, that is, Ukraine
в четырнадцатом году Ну то есть Украина
fought with Russia since fourteenth year, it
воевала с Россией с четырнадцатого года
turns out yes, well, you think yes Well, yes, that
получается да ну считаете да Ну да то
is, it turns out If it weren't for Russia, then
есть получается Если бы не Россия то
no one there would have shot at your house it
никто бы там не стрелял по твоему дому
turns out
получается
Yes, well, this is already a separate question
Да ну это идёт уже отдельный вопрос по
about it turns out refusal it turns out
поводу получается отказа получается
Ukraine did not have
Украина
any weapons in Donbass
вое у ша Донбасса никакого никакого
I'm older I can
оружия не было я старше я могу
interrupt Shakhtar Donbass had
перебивать у Шахтёра Донбасса были
just sticks Yes, some and someone, then,
просто палки Да какие-то а кто-то значит
fought with Ukraine there with tanks Arty
воевал с Украиной там танками Арти
other question is about something else you
другом вопрос идт о другом вы
understand I'm talking about what started with what it
понимаете Я говорю о том что началось с
all started with the fact that Ukraine
чего всё началось с того что Украина
decided to actually join
решила собственно вступить в состав
Europe Well, that is, NATO, all of this, and it
Европы Ну то есть НАТО вот этого всего и
turned out that the
получилось так что
territory of Donbass refused this
территория Донбасса отказалась от этого
And after that, no, it didn't refuse No, in the
И после этого нет не отказывалась Нет в
sense that a territory as a territory can
смысле территория как территория может
refuse to refuse, some
отказаться отказаться могут какие-то
people can make a decision on the
люди принять решение
territory of power, just no Look, not the
территория власти как раз нет Смотри не
Donetsk Regional Council, the Lugansk
Донецкий областной Совет Луганский
Regional Council did not take any action about this,
областной Совет ничего об этом не
some came from Russia, why are
принимал пришли какие-то из ро сза что
they the power here, they are now the DPR and that's it in
они тут власть они теперь ДНР и вс вот в
Lugansk and  in Donetsk were officially
Луганске и в Донецке были официально
elected by all deputies to all the peoples of the
избраны всеми депутата всем народам
Donetsk and Lugansk regions deputies Yes,
Донецкой и Луганской области депутаты Да
in the year some people from Russia came
в м году пришли какие-то люди из России
with machine guns said that they are no longer
с автоматами сказали что они теперь не
deputies and that's all they are now in power I
депутаты и всё они теперь власть
want a cut you when you just sat in a hat
хочу подрез ты когда просто в шапке
funny you looked like you when you
сидел смешной ты выглядел как ты когда
started talking you confirmed it in short Come
начал разговаривать ты короче подтвердил
on hello Hello
Давай здравствуйте Здравствуйте Вы
Where are you from Russia Well I can see by the situation
откуда из России Ну я вижу по обстановке
what city And how by the situation by the
город какой А как по обстановке по
situation Well how is the design
обстановке Ну как дизайн
Russian design
российский дизайн
Rollano Acra do it not European
ролано Акра делают это не Европейский
design where from What city and the city of
дизайн откуда Из какого города а город
hundred disappeared I understood it is interesting you know such
ста пропали понял интересно знаете такой
Yes I know from there also this Gorbachev from
Да знаю оттуда же ещё этот Горбачёв со
Stavropol o Right
Ставрополья о Верно
right I have My father is just
правильно у меня У меня просто отец
from Mineralnye Vody O cool Fellowship
родом из Минеральных Вод О классно
turns out Well almost Earth
Земляк получается Ну почти Земля
well y Well the region there is good mileage it is
ну й Ну край там километраж хороший это
in this region Well 200
в этом крае Ну 200
Yes what brought you to chat
Да что вас привело в чат
roulette just well nothing to do boring
рулетку просто ну делать нечего скучно
What do you think why Russia attacked
Как считаете почему Россия напала на
Ukraine there were many prerequisites for this
Украину для этого было много предпосылок
So why did it
Так а почему
attack it was necessary to defend
напало надо было защищать
Donbass defended Donbass yes
Донбасс защитили Донбасс да
where Well how
где Ну как
where in fact on the maps in fact that here is the
где по факту по картам по факту что вот
city of Bakhmut you attacked it to
город бахмут вы напали на него чтобы
protect it yeah 70,000 people lived there you ca
защитить его угу Там жило 70.000
n't protect brother I'm sorry I
населения не защитить брат я Извини
misspoke but to liberate liberate super
оговорился а освободить освободить супер
to clarify good here is the city of Bakhmut you
во уточнение хорошее вот город бахмут вы
liberated Artemovsk Yes they liberated
освободили Артёмовск Да освободили
how many people lived in Bakhmut before liberation
сколько до освобождения жило в бахмуте
Probably you 70,000 people 70,000
людей Наверное ты 70.000 людей 70.000
population of Bakhmut was Yes what is the
населени бахмута было Да сколько
population of Bakhmut after
населения бахмута после
liberation probably 100
освобождения наверное 100
zero there is simply nothing no living
ноль там нету просто ничего ни живых
buildings nothing no infrastructure no
зданий ничего ни инфраструктуры там
one lives there stupidly solida out of 15,000 But the
никто не живёт тупо солида из 15.000 Но
question is whose country's flag do you have or Germany
вопрос У вас флаг чй страны или Германия
I've been living in Germany for 18 years already and this is
Я живу в Германии 18 лет уже а это
Germany black red yellow Yes but here's the
Германия чёрный красный жёлтый Да а вот
question it turns out yes if Russia
вопрос получается да если Россия
liberated Bakhmut before liberation
освободила бахмут до освобождения там
70,000 people lived there after liberation
жило 70.000 населения после освобождения
zero doesn't it seem strange to you that
ноль вам не кажется что что-то странное
liberation no And from what were
освобождение нет А от чего освободили
these people liberated from their
этих людей от ихних
homes Well come on yes Well if it's more
домов Ну давай да Ну если тебе так
convenient for you come on  no no I'm interested in how I am a
удобнее давай не не Мне интересно как
citizen of Russia and you are a citizen of
вот я гражданин России и вы гражданин
Russia Yes but I just live in Germany You
России Да но я просто живу в Германии Вы
live in Russia explain to me a citizen of
живёте в России объясните мне гражданину
Russia who lives in Germany how our
России который живёт в Германии как наша
Russia freed people in Bakhmut from
Россия освободила людей в бахмуте от
their houses I just don't understand how a
ихних домов просто не понимаю как
citizen of Russia of the Russian Federation
гражданин России Российской Федерация
can wear such a cap Why And what is prohibited here I don't understand No it is not
может носить такую кепку Почему А что у
prohibited I don't understand on Why in an
запрещено мне непонятно на Почему
incomprehensible
непонятном
way and surrendered here Hands Up and surrendered No
мым и сдались вот Руки Вверх и сдали Нет
I'll explain to you look The fact is that our
я тебе объясню смотри Дело в том что наш
prince Vladimir who baptized Rus' here
князь Владимир который крестил Русь вот
on his coins is the same trident sign This is the
на его монетах этот же знак тризуб Это
sign of Prince
знак князя
Vladimir You do not renounce Prince
Владимира Вы же не отрекайтесь от князя
Vladimir the Orthodox
Владимира православного
our from yours
нашего от вашего
Look who yours is on the Russian coin
Смотри вот кого ваше на монету русского
this is the Russian prince Vladimir prince of Rus'
это же русский князь Владимир князь Руси
So you also get Russian I am a
Так ты тоже русский получаешь я ж Я же
citizen of the Russian Federation I
гражданин Российской Федерации я тебе
tell you again I am from Krasnodar So so well I have
ещё раз говорю я из Краснодара родом Так
been living in Germany for 18 years in 2
так ну живу 18 лет в Германии через 2
years there will be a twenty So what am I
года будет двадцатка Так и что мне
not allowed We are not at
нельзя Мы же не находимся в состоянии
war with Ukraine so it is forbidden to
войны с Украиной чтобы нельзя было
wear their symbols we have a war no
носить их символику у нас война не
declared to Russia Ukraine I do not know no
объявлена России Украине не знаю никто в
sane person in Russia wears
России из здравых людей не носит
symbols Why is it so I see it's just in
символику Почему так я я смотрю просто в
Russia They ban it yes for It's illegal to
России Запрещают это да за Это незаконно
detain no ban sensibly
задерживают ни не запрещают здраво
Human I sing to you This is why Ukraine is a
Челове я те пою Это почему Украина - это
Slavic state our Slavic
Славянское государство наш Славянский
brother w Why in Ukraine no one
брат ш Почему в Украине никто
goes out there with the Russian flag Well
не не выходит там с российским флагом Ну
maybe because because
может из-за того что из-за того что
Russia attacked Ukraine and they have martial
Россия напала на Украину и у них военное
law introduced in Ukraine as far as I
положение введено в Украине насколько я
know Understand they are in a state of war we are not in so
знаю Поня они в состоянии войны мы не в
question how we Russians
со сказать вопрос как мы россияне
liberated the residents of Bakhmut If before
освободили жителей бахмута Если до
liberation they
освобождения они
went to work 7 check studied got married
7 чек ходили на работу учились женились
And so on And after liberation
И так дальше А после Наго освобождения
some of them died and their houses are gone
часть из них погибла а домов ихних
at all
вообще
yes this is the fog of war And where where do
нет да это туман войны А где где сейчас
all these liberated residents of Bakhmut live now
живут все эти жители бахмута
Well 7000 Yes where do they live no
освобождённые Ну 7000 Да где они не не
where in Russia live And where where
где-то в России живут А где где
in Western Ukraine that's for sure yes So where did they
на Западной Украине это точно да Так где
give 70,000 apartments to these people this is a whole
дали 70.000 квартир этим людям это целый
city New DPR LPR  Voronezh Kursk
город Новый ДНР лнр Воронеж Курск
Belgorod and further across Russia Farther So where is
Белгород и дальше по России Дале Так где
this money Where are these apartments no one
где эти деньги Где эти квартиры никто не
gave in Kursk look in Kursk in Kursk
давал в Курске смотри в Курске в Курске
even those who are residents of the Kursk region
даже тем кто жителе Курской области
who were evacuated they were not given
которые эвакуированы им не дали
apartments whose houses were destroyed even
квартиры у которых дома разрушены дажи
I
У меня
just have me my cousin in
просто меня у меня двоюродный брат в
Kursk lives in Kursk itself not in the
Курске живёт в самом Курске не на
occupied territory wants to live know
оккупированной территори хочет жит зна
that People are given a
что Люд дают
certificate here they dont give it look these se
сертифика вот не дают смотри этих се
firstly they started to issue secondly there is no
во-первых начали выдавать вовторых на
certificate for this housing in the Kursk
сертификата нету этого жилья в Курской
region there is no housing for residents of the Kursk
области нету жилья для жителей Курской
region everything is there where nowhere 7
области всё есть то куда не куда 7
7 residents of Bakhmut half a million Mariupol
7 жителе бахмута полмиллиона Мариуполя
where earlier please And where did they go for
куда ране пожалуйста А куда делись
example there how many fled from Ukraine
например там вот сколько из Украины
I dont know [ __ ] I dont live I dont live
бежали Я не знаю сри я не живу я не живу
in Ukraine about 3 million people approximately
в Украине примерно 3 млн людей примерно
so where did they go that is it
так куда они делись то есть вот
turns out because of this war yes 3 million
получается из-за войны этой да 3 мл
people now live in Russia without
людей сейчас в России живёт без
apartments
квартир
Why did they come where they gave a certificate for
Почему приехали ку дали сертификат на
each family buying a
каждую семью покупка
home dont tell fables  look look
жилья не рассказывай басни посмотри
Now no look Now I'm
посмотри Сейчас нет посмотри Сейчас я
turning off the sound for you so that you don't
тебе отключаю звук чтобы ты короче не
listen to me in short now look then take and
слушал меня теперь смотри значит возьми
look how much housing was given to refugees
и посмотри сколько выдали беженцам жилья
zero zero housing in Russia was given to refugees
ноль ноль жилья в России выдали беженцам
from Ukraine come on show
из Украины давай
show where those 3 million are just the ones
покажи покажи где эти 3 млн только
you're on oh-oh-oh
который ты по ой-ой-ой
That's it come on I beat you come on
Всё давай я тебя победил давай
Hello Good evening Where are you
Здравствуйте Добрый вечер Вы
from We're from Moscow and in Moscow Were
откуда Мы из Москвы а в Москву Приехали
you born somewhere or were you born there I understand You also have a partner and The partner
понял У вас ещё напарница а Напарник
understood what's there and how do you communicate I
понял что там там а чём общаетесь
communicate like damn well we without you
я так общаемся типа блин ну мы без
know without this like well you're from
знаешь без это типа ну ты вот с
Ukraine What are you communicating about I'm not saying you're from
Украины Ты о чём общаетесь
Ukraine yes I'm from Ukraine I asked And how do you communicate I'm not
Украины Я спросил А чем общаетесь не я
saying we no claims how would you
говорю мы без претензий как бы ты тебе
normally communicate with us like that I have no
нормально общаться с нами так я без
claims I communicate normally well what what
претензий я нормально общаюсь
could Look what
а ну а что какие могут Смотри какие
claims could there be against you like I
могут быть к вам претензии типа я же
understand that from you You know you
понимаю что от вас Ты знаешь вот это
read the news Yes you read Look not from
читаешь новости Да читаешь Смотри не от
you don't stop Look I  I'll tell you my position right away
вас не стоп Смотри я сразу свою позицию
I understand that nothing
скажу я понимаю что от вас ничего не
depends on you in Russia, it does
зависит в России
n't even depend on me in Ukraine since the
даже нет от меня зависит в Украине со
time of Ancient Rome there was a principle Yes that a
времён Древнего Рима было принцип Да что
slave is not responsible for his
раб не несёт ответственности за своего
master to Putin We have no complaints against
хозяина к Путину У нас есть претензии к
you from the bottom of our hearts bro Honestly, this is the first
Вам нет от души братан Вот честно первый
time we've met a Ukrainian
раз мы сейчас встречаем вот украинца
who generally thinks adequately there,
которые вот вообще там адекватно как бы
yeah In fact, you're right because
вот да На самом деле ты прав потому что
seriously Listen, but you have this there they
ну серьёзно Слушай а вот у тебя это там
touch Him, look, look, look,
ц трогают Ниго чит смотри чит смотри
Putin, so nothing depends on you Yes,
Путина так от тебя ничего не зависит Да
what difference does it make to you what's going on
какая тебе разница что там происходит у
in our
нас в
country, no interest, interest,
стране не интерес интерес вот интерес
look, I'll tell you, as a free
смотри я тебе скажу я как свободный
person, I can teach you how to at least
человек я вот могу научить тебя как хотя
see, as
увидеть как
it were, the Horizon of Freedom in your country so that
бы Горизонт Свободы в твоей стране чтобы
you can
ты возможно
possibly wait, don't interrupt No, you can't, you
возможно подожди не перебивай Нет нельзя
can't, because freedom doesn't interrupt a person
нельзя потому что свободно человека не
if you Yes want at least your
если ты Да хочешь чтобы хотя бы твои
children to stop being Yes, you need to
дети перестали быть Да нужно
think about it already What to do in your
задумываться уже Что делать в своей
country so that if not you, then your
стране так чтобы если не ты то твои
children become free What do you think can be
дети стали свободными Как ты считаешь
done in Russia so that your
что можно сделать в России чтобы твои
children are no longer like you under involuntary confinement
дети уже не были как ты под невольным
slaves And your children are free I asked him a
рабами А твои дети свободны я ему задал
question Well
вопрос Ну
I feel free too, just like you do
я себя чувствую тоже свободным как и ты
in fact so stop again let's do it this way
на самом деле так стоп ещё раз давай так
I say it means that something depends on me in my country
я говорю значит я от меня в моей стране
I am
что-то зависит я
elected I am responsible for this country
избирают Я ответственный за эту страну
Let's do it again one more time now I am
Давай ещё раз ещё раз теперь я тебя
asking you it depends on you in your country
спрашиваю от тебя в твоей стране что-то
of course we voted together so
зависит конечно мы голосовали вдвоём так
wait I am with you vari
подожди тный я с тобой вари
zeny What is your
зены Как тебя
name Sasha Sasha Look Yes we are with
зовут Саша Саша Вот смотри Да мы вот с
you now remember Yes that
тобой сейчас пом Да вот что от тебя
depends on you I mean that depends Well that is
зависит В смысле что зависит Ну то есть
in what context are you asking this
в каком контексте ты это спрашиваешь
if you are talking about elections let's say
если ты говоришь про выборы вот допустим
you don't have them and never will I
вот у тебя их нет наху и не буде Я
asked wait I just with what
спросил подожди я просто с что от тебя
depends on you in your
зависит в твоей
country personally that is my opinion as a person for
стране лично вот моё мнение как человека
example well we have elections That is
например ну у нас есть выборы То есть
if you are not sure of their uh freedom I for
если ты не уверен в их ээ свободе Я
example am not sure of your elections
например не уверен в твоих выборах
because wait let's do it again let's do it
потому что подожди давай своих ещё раз
what depends on you not about me
давай что от тебя зависит не про меня
now we are talking about me let's do it about
сейчас про говорим про меня давай про
you what depends on you in your country
тебя что от тебя зависит в твоей стране
specifically That is about me let's do it here we are  I
конкретно Вот про меня давай вот мы на Я
work I have a job in which in
работаю у меня есть работа в которой в
work in which some
работе в которой от меня какие-то
actions depend on me That is, how can you only
действия зави То есть ты как ты только
work yes work from the word well
работать можешь да работа от слова ну
wait Well, what do you want so that we without
подожди Ну а что ты хочешь чтобы мыж без
labor no sostoya little green wait
труда нет состо так зелёненький подожди
I'm talking to Sasha CH Sanya look Sanya once again
я с Сашей говорю ЧР Саня смотри Саня ещё
let's put the question directly
раз я давай так поставлю прямо
who should report to whom Putin
кто перед кем должен отчитываться Путин
to you or you to Putin the
перед тобой или ты перед
government to the people or the People
Путиным власть перед народом или Народ
to the government Putin the government should
перед властью Путин власть должна
report to the
отчитаться перед
people demand what will happen what will happen to
народом спрос что будет что будет с
you if you go
тобой если ты
to Moscow to Red Square with a poster with a
в Москву на Красную Площадь с плакатом с
question to Putin Putin why do we have
вопросом Путину Путин почему у нас
low salaries What will happen to you we are
низкие зарплаты Что будет с тобой нас
already
уже
Glu No well what will happen a second connection
Глу Не ну что будет секунду связ
about
про
connection zayu in will be with with a
связ заю во будет с
question to Putin Putin why do we have
с вопросом Путину Путин почему у нас
low salaries What will happen to
низкие зарплаты Что будет с
you I have a high salary that just
тобой у меня высокая зарплата что просто
look what will happen if you
смотри что будет если ты вот таким
go out with such a poster
плакатом выйдешь
press that is in theory If I were there yes back and forth
наж то есть в теории Если бы я там да
yes it is clear that we will not go out with
туда-сюда да понятно что мы не выйдем с
such a poster really why Well because
таким плакатом реально почему Ну потому
let's so what will happen if you  you will go
что давай так что будет если ты выйдешь
to Red Square with a poster Putin
на Красную Площадь с плакатом Путин
Why are salaries higher in the US than in
Почему в США зарплаты выше чем в
Russia
России
[laughter] that's it no no no
[смех]
Hang out again
всё не не не Зависай ещё раз
look at myself I will repeat the question What will happen to
смотри са я повторю вопрос Что будет с
you if you go to Red Square
тобой если ты выйдешь на Красную Площадь
with a poster Putin Why are salaries higher in the US
с плакатом Путин Почему в США зарплаты
than in Russia you if you see if
выше чем в России ты если ты видишь если
you go out with the same question in Kyiv
ты выйдешь с таким же вопросом в Киеве
Believe me you I will go out come on look
Поверь мне у тебя я выйду давай смотри
Let's conduct an experiment green one
Давай проведём эксперимент зелёненький
wait green one green one quiet come on
подожди зелёненький зелёненький тихо
look I am now I am sitting in the city of
давай смотри я сейчас я сижу в городе
Khmelnitsky Ukraine I can freely
Хмельницке Украина я могу свободно
say for example
сказать например
Poroshenko Zelensky you can
Порошенко Зеленский ты можешь про своих
say this about your tops If I were against
топов сказать такое Если бы я был против
Putin I would say Yes but okay you can
Путина я бы сказал Да но хорошо можешь
say about any at least one politician of Russia that he
сказать что он
[music] is
[музыка]
not on the living on the living Russian
не на живых на живых российских
politicians regional authorities Yes Don't give it well topo come on
политиков региональной власти Да Не
look I Come on
давай ну топо давай смотри я Давай
deputies of the Supreme deputies of the State Duma you
депутаты Верховного депутаты госдумы
understand we live in Moscow and we have our own
понимаешь мы живём в Москве и у нас соя
job look again Come on I can do this
работа ещё раз смотри Давай так я могу
I can say this about anyone
сказа вот я про любого могу
again, no matter how I
сказать ещ раз независимо от того как я
feel about them, I won't do anything to Monet,
к ним отношусь я Моне ничего не
but you're afraid. Tell me about at least one
а ты боишься Скажи хоть про одного
Russian. Look,
российского смотри давай так смотри
let's look. Come on, Putin is good. Putin is good.
Давай Путин хорошо Путин у вас хороший
Well, there must be someone bad from the State Duma,
Ну кто-то же есть плохой из Госдумы
at least one bad person from the government. I don't
плохой из правительства хоть один не
know. Everything is good here in Moscow. We don't
знаю у нас в Москве Всё хорошо Не
doubt it, not directly. For example, I'm not
сомневаемся не напрямую Я например не
interested in someone's life. What are you
увлекаюсь там чьей-то жизнью что вы
saying? I know him. You only know
говорит что вот я его знаю он только
Yeltsin. Yes, because he died. You
Ельцина знаете да потому что он умер про
can tell me about him. I'll explain to you. Look.
него можно сказать я тебе объясню смотри
What's the difference? Not a
В чём отличие в Киеве не открылась ни
single new metro station has opened in Kyiv compared to.
одна новая станция метро по сравнению с
Look, let's not. No, we're not necessary. We're
смотри давай не не надо мы мы сейчас
talking about freedom now. Come on,
рассказываем про свободу Давай сейчас
about freedom. Come on, don't throw in a manual. Don't hang around. Don't hang around.
про свободу Давай ты методичку не
I want
накидывай не Зависай не Зависай Я хочу
you. Don't hang around. Baby,
тебя не Зависай Малыш
these. They're running. They're running. Now,
этих бегут бегут сейчас а
ta-ta-ta.
та-та-та
Yes, they're hanging in such poses.
Да вот в таких позах и
Yes, we're free. Yes, we're on a
зависли Да да мы свободный да
knife. There was movement inside.
снутри движ
It was all just a divine dressing down. Yes,
всё это был просто Божественный разнос я
Yeltsin Yeltsin Now about a dead
да Ельцин Ельцин Вот про мёртвого
politician they can they can trample him with their
политика они могут они могут его топтать
feet anyone but about their living one no
ногами лю но про ихнего живого ни про
one in that is the difference between any
кого в том и отличается любая
democratic country Yes from an authoritarian
Демократическая страна Да от авторитарно
democratic they can talk there about Trump
демократическом могут говорить там на
Biden Zelensky Poroshenko there
трампа байдена Зеленского Порошенко там
Merkel Scholz Macron People because
Меркель шольц макрона Люди потому что
people are the source of power they elect a
люди есть источник власти они избирают
person and they can make claims against him
человека и они могут к нему претензии
They can say that he is so
выдвигать Они могут говорить что он
he is bad Yes that is not he This is an
такой он плохой Да вот он не Это
expectation no they can not Russia is the
ожидание не они не могут Россия это
only country in which they are simply
единственная страна в которой они просто
satisfied with all their deputies
удовлетворены всеми своими депутатами
those
теми
officials will be everything he is even afraid to
чиновниками буде всё он даже боится
just say name at least one It
просто сказать назвать хоть одного Это
was a great video It's a pity that the
был прекрасный ролик Жалко что зависли
like squeak comment is frozen subscribe to
лайк писка комент подпишись на й
Telegram right now axis VN and
Telegram прям зараз ось ВН а
Popik this is very and very important YouTube is
Попик це дуже и дуже важливо YouTube
busy with us through scarg Orcs in your ban and
заня нас через скарг Орки в твый бан и
very many videos are not shown to people at
дуже багато видео не показуе людям
times are not shown information about streams
вчасно не показуе информация про стрими
That is why  we Mali operational
Тому для того щоб ми Мали оперативний
link is written right now and while there in
звязок пишиться прямо зараз а пок там в
telegram okm video there is also interesting and
телегра окм видео ще теж цикава и
useful information and we are obliged to you to
корисна информация и мы повинни з вами
keep the current operational link
тримати постийний оперативный звязок
independently in that che will show you the process
незалежно в того чи покаже вам проце
YouTube Glory to Ukraine letter
YouTube Слава украини пись
L
L